I'm not a lonely old man.
I'm here with my wife,
moving into our Yangliu Xincheng together.
Coming to this retirement community
isn't because my children are unfilial.
I'm just here because
life is convenient here,
and there's full medical care.
Most importantly,
everyone here
is about my age.
I'm here to have fun.
About the same age...
Having fun...
Professor Zhu,
so you admit you're here to have fun too.
But that doesn't include him.
As soon as I see him,
I can't smile anymore.
What?
You're here?
I'm leaving.
What's going on here?
An interview?
Yes, field research.
Just documenting things.
By the way, Yusheng,
I've been meaning to ask you.
This place of ours...
it's not rural farmland,
so why do you call it "field research"?
Yeah.
Doesn't that make us all field mice?
And wouldn't Gou'er Ye become a field dog?
Who are you calling a lapdog?
Professor Fan, how did this happen?
Here, sit down quickly.
Is it bleeding?
No.
No need.
Don't keep covering it.
No blood.
Just a bump.
Gou'er Ye, you really are...
Where is he?
Look at that.
That old man runs so fast.
Understood.
Your field research.
Specifically...
social research.
Right.
Is my understanding correct?
Yes.
As expected of Boss Li.
Your comprehension is strong.
So here's the question.
You went to all this trouble...
to come to our retirement community...
to investigate us...
what is it for?
Survey sampling.
Data collection.
By analyzing your generation of seniors...
we hope to reach a universal conclusion.
You...
analyze us?
Can you understand our era?
Have you experienced what we went through?
I think we can.
Because we are approaching it from...
a sociological perspective.
No perspective will work.
Studying us?
Kids these days...
Can't carry on your shoulders...
can't lift with your hands...
Lazy,
and ignorant of life's basics.
That's not right.
Society is always progressing.
Each new generation surpasses the last.
Each generation is better than the last.
That's not necessarily true.
Historically speaking, each generation improves.
However...
occasionally there are one or two generations...
that might be exceptions.
The West had The Beat Generation.
Here we have the lying-flat generation.
Lying flat is a minority, after all.
Look at me, didn't I get up early?
Shut up.
You're the most unreliable one of this generation.
You compare yourselves to us?
How can you compare?
The hardships we endured...
the books we read...
the things we experienced...
To compare with us...
besides playing video games...
what else can you compare with?
But we are young
We have new knowledge
New concepts
New skills
From intelligence to physical strength
From explosiveness to endurance
Then we are definitely
stronger than you guys
If you put it that way
then let's have a competition
As for the specific events
we'll go back and think about it
We're competing against them?
They are all young and strong
You didn't even discuss it with me beforehand
Old age isn't about physical strength
It's agreed
We won't do those jumping and running events
If it weren't for my head injury
like a trivia quiz
those youngsters definitely wouldn't beat me
We'd win no matter what we played
That's not necessarily true
With Professor Fan's vocabulary
if we compete in memorizing words
we might not actually beat him
Otherwise, let's compete in eating
I don't believe that in this area
anyone can outdo me
Don't talk nonsense
Old people shouldn't overeat
Besides
even if you really won
that would only prove
that our generation are all foodies
Competing in talents and skills
We're not sloppy about that either
I've been a star performer since I was little
Recitation, clapper talk, crosstalk, three-and-a-half sentences
There's nothing I can't handle
Who wasn't a star performer?
I seriously learned the ukulele before third grade
No issues other than it sounding terrible
I could dance when I was little too
They always put me in the front row for welcoming guests
That...
Beautiful flowers are blooming
My arms and legs are old now
It's a bit lacking
This won't work anymore
I also learned a couple of hometown opera pieces as a kid
It's just been a long time since I sang
I've forgotten it all
Alright
These can all be competition events
I...
I did practice piano for a few days in the past
but I've forgotten most of it now
It's okay
You can brush up on it
It'll surely work
Okay
You count as one entry
I'll bring out my treasured masterpiece
Dingjun Shan, and show it off to them
Let these kids really experience
the profoundness of our traditional Chinese culture
Yingzi
how about you?
Me?
I really don't have any talents
I just studied hard growing up
Oh, right
I entered a typing contest in middle school
At the time, I won an
eighth prize
That's not...
I think that's enough
Before the grandpas and grandmas even get to Yingzi
it'll already be three to zero
They'll be totally wiped out
Children
look here
what can I do?
You just rest
You don't need to get involved personally
Who?
Who is pregnant?
If you ask me
this is enough
We'll end the battle three to zero
Don't say we're bullying the kids
Right
It's settled then
It's getting late.
And there's quite a crowd.
Let's get started.
The first match.
The Clapper Talk duel.
The opposing sides are...
Zhu Zhu from the Youth Team...
versus Mr. Liang Shengtian from the Seniors Team.
Well then...
I will perform a piece for everyone...
a classic Clapper Talk...
"Rescue from the Prison Cart."
Great!
Good!
Don't clap for him.
Why keep clicking the clappers without speaking?
I'm about to speak.
Good!
That was amazing! Come on.
Let's look at our judges.
Come on.
After a unanimous decision by our judges...
for this Youth-Senior competition...
the first round of Clapper Talk...
the winner is, from the Seniors Team...
Mr. Liang Shengtian!
Yay!
Let me say a few words.
I think this young man is quite good.
He plays the clappers well.
The key is he dared to choose this old piece.
And his lyrics were rock solid.
A real talent.
I propose...
that we both be tied for champion in this match.
Great!
Uncle Liang...
you were really awesome too.
Still going strong.
It's a tie!
Now, next is the intense...
second round of competition.
First up is our...
beloved, respected...
and adorable Boss Li...
Mr. Li Jianguo!
Boss Li!
Go for it!
I'll do my humble best then.
I'll sing a piece of traditional Peking Opera...
"Dingjun Shan."
Good!
See that?
He's got the moves.
Bravo!
This is a true traditional treasure.
Exactly. You've secured the score for this round.
Grandpa Li has profound skills.
He sang really well.
I'll also learn from his example...
and sing a piece of traditional treasure...
Henan Opera...
"Mu Guiying Takes Command."
Good! Go Xiao Xin!
Go Xiao Xin!
Let's go!
Let's go-go!
See that?
We've got the moves too.
Bravo!
Xiao Xin!
Boss Li! Xiao Xin!
Boss Li!
Everyone, please settle down.
Auntie Xiao Cai.
As everyone has seen,
these are different genres.
The performance levels are both excellent.
You're making it for us judges...
very hard to judge.
I think...
our Boss Li was still...
just a tiny, little bit better.
Why do I feel like...
our Xiao Xin won by a narrow margin?
I think Peking Opera...
is a cut above.
National quintessence.
That's right.
Doesn't Henan Opera count as National quintessence?
It counts too.
But the singing...
is still not...
They were both wonderful!
They are both National quintessence.
What is the most commendable thing?
It's that a young Gen Z girl
can also love the classics
and respect tradition.
This is also...
truly praiseworthy.
Isn't it?
I'll follow Comrade Old Liang's example.
I suggest...
that for this competition, Xiao Xin and I
should also be joint champions.
Great!
Boss Li!
Thank you, Boss Li!
That's about enough.
What are you all laughing at?
We hustled all morning,
and didn't win a single point.
It really turned into "friendship first, competition second."
Stop giggling.
Winning or losing concerns
the reputation of our older generation.
We must win the afternoon match.
We need to step it up, classmates.
The competition this morning...
we won by sheer luck.
We didn't win, either.
Weren't they all draws?
A draw is better than losing.
I didn't expect the seniors to be so skilled.
They're all really amazing.
Because they chose all the events.
So, what's the next event?
The event for the third match is...
Speed typing.
The participant for the Youth Team is...
Xie Yingzi.
Yingzi!
The participant for the Seniors Team is...
To be determined.
Okay.
Boss Li.
Our participant for this event...
hasn't been decided yet?
We don't have a participant for this event.
No participant?
Do we have anyone?
Typing.
Type my foot.
Do we have anyone?
Old Fan.
Don't you type all the time?
The clicking and clacking keeps me awake.
I'm no good at that.
You call that typing?
I just peck with one finger.
My comrades call it the "woodpecker style."
Then what do we do?
Are we just...
going to forfeit and admit defeat?
Don't do that.
If there's no other way,
I know how to type.
How about...
I give it a try?
Try what?
We have someone.
He'll do it.
Please.
Ready...
Go!
Thirty seconds
Twenty seconds
Fifteen seconds
Ten seconds
Come on!
Steady!
Three
Two
One
Stop
Alright,
let me check
the results for both contestants.
Youth Team,
Xie Yingzi's per-minute
character count is
219.
A sure win.
Elder Team,
Mr. Rudy Kraut's
per-minute character count is
two hundred
and twenty-four.
Okay.
I declare
that for our third event,
the winner of Speed Typing is
Mr. Rudy Kraut.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I am not the winner.
Why is that?
It's because...
although
I did type more characters than her,
however,
there are three errors in mine.
Three errors.
Whereas she has no errors.
So the winner should be her.
Alright.
Then I declare
that for our
third competition event,
the winner of Speed Typing is
Xie Yingzi.
We're in trouble, big trouble.
Looks like we're going to lose.
Who's to blame?
It's all on you.
You and Boss Li.
A game of chess you clearly had in the bag,
and you somehow played it to a draw.
What were you doing?
Taking our seniors' honor
just to do someone a favor?
Who would have thought Rudy, that foreigner,
would lose to Yingzi?
We lost because of him.
Alright.
Between us, we're
hundreds of years old.
Let's not fight among ourselves.
The most important thing now is to figure out
how we can win this back.
Right.
We have to count on Teacher Liu
to win it back for us.
With Teacher Liu, how could we lose?
That's right.
Yeah. Come on!
These grandpas and grandmas are amazing.
But,
we still managed to score a precious point.
This precious point
was given to us out of their noble generosity.
Actually, my few lines of Henan Opera
couldn't compare to Boss Li's.
And my bit of clapper talk
was no match for Uncle Liang.
If I asked him to be my mentor,
do you think he'd accept me?
Alright.
Stop putting yourselves down.
Keke,
how is your ukulele preparation going?
I...
Everyone,
I think the break is just about over.
Shall we continue?
Sure.
You... I mean...
Teacher Liu, you just...
Uncles and Aunties,
let's
continue.
Continue.
Let's go. Let's go.
Let's go.
Teacher Liu, you go first.
Teacher Liu goes first.
Hurry up.
It's okay.
Next up is our
final competition event:
the singing contest.
The first to perform
is the singer from our Youth Team,
Xia Keke.
Keke!
Go for it!
Good luck!
Next, I will sing for you all.
I hope you like it.
Great!
So,
we thank Xia Keke very much
for such an unexpected performance.
And next,
is...
I personally believe
this is the moment you have all been
looking forward to the most these past few days.
Please welcome the singer from our Seniors Team,
Teacher Liu Minzhi.
Yay!
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
The song I'm going to sing for you is
"I Love You, China."
Great!
Bravo!
Alright,
Teacher Liu,
tell me,
what was the point of all that?
We competed so hard for so long,
only to end in a draw.
Isn't that like we didn't compete at all?
A total waste of effort.
It wasn't a waste.
After today's competition,
we truly feel that
many of our old ideas
have changed.
That's right.
We realized that
from you grandpas and grandmas,
there is so much we can learn.
When you were young,
you must have all been the cream of the crop.
In short,
you are all incredible.
By that logic,
you also taught us a lesson.
We have to admit,
indeed, each new generation surpasses the last.
Each generation is stronger than the next.
No, no.
Isn't that Gou'er Ye?
Gou'er Ye!
Why are you running away?